Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Alright.
Mike: Wait, sorry, before we go, would it be feasible to start a half hour earlier?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah.
Mike: Just start.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Tim, you need a soundboard with that… with that recording in progress, and like, whenever things get too slow, just hit it a few times.
Tim Sackton: Kong… Kong runs the sound now, so…
David S. Kong: I'm just so on track.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Correct.
David S. Kong: Keep staring at this robot in the room, in the library.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): this party of misfits from Tolin.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): were engaged by, Lord Hulda to go through a door in his basement and break a treaty held by the man on the other side. They go through.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Finding that on the other side is a Faey lord who has been tricked into an agreement with his neighbor up the road.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): who turns out to have been the head of a Drancoran society.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): policing the holes between different planes, although your characters might not know or comprehend it exactly, between different planes and spheres and boundaries in the universe of Talgar.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Going into that, end.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Lord Ending says, I can't break this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Unless you bring me the glass key.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That locks the door at the center of the house.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The party moves on and enters the house, Finding it, infuriatingly
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): a sort of a giant Rubik's Cube of rooms, that move across three different axes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Moving from one room to another, you discover that…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All of the rooms that you've moved through are built around a central prison that doesn't move, and the rooms.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: things push…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That central prison through different coordinates in space and in time, so that whatever is trapped inside it
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): can't get out… can't make its way out of that thing. There's some suggestion that if it was in one space and time, this thing would be able to puzzle its way out from inside of its locked prison, where it's been put by…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The, erythramo slimperum, a Drancurian secret society.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They're accompanied on the journey through the Rubik's Cube house, the 27th room, it's called, for the prison at the center of it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): by the, cartographer and mathematician Menestheus, who was a junior member of the order tracked with, or charged, rather, with keeping track of where all of these weak points or holes in the universe are.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And guiding people to and from them. So he doesn't have much useful to say about the contents of this place, because he hasn't really been inside before. He's only brought folks here, and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): was left behind at Lord Endlessly Ending's party, possibly as a sacrifice, possibly because he got drunk and fell asleep.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): At the end of the previous session, you started in a fungal greenhouse, where,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Calypsies, an ancient dwarven…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): wizard and gardener and fungal researcher and self-described head of the order, after the depth of the previous head of the order, is working on creating a fungus golem body in which to put her
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Consciousness? Question mark? Soul? question mark? In order to, make her way safely out of the house, and then presumably restart the order, question mark?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They leave her to it and continue to proceed through the house. We find a lecture hall with, diagrams of dandelion life cycles and a black-on-black painting of a hole in the universe through which something has come.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In the next room is, Clockworks, where the grandfather clocks and desk clocks are manufactured, and Tarek,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Importantly, I'll remind this because he's not here this session, picks up a desk-sized clock that is working and tracks and, you know, shows you the year and the coordinate location of where you are in each room that you move through.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Or, excuse me, shows you the year and coordinate location of the central prison room, location, each time you step from one room to another.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In the next room, it's one of those big mechanical rooms, and you hear the transcriptions of, something with an unending, thirst for
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Dreamers are for souls, something that's fallen in love with them and just can't, like, an addict get enough of it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In the next room, it's an animal experimentation lab, and there are mushroom men there who attack Ministheus, wound him very badly, actually drop him below zero, but you rescue killing and burning both infected bodies, but Ministheus is…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Infected.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Charo took a pretty bad hit, too. I will just remind him and others in the party.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They keep on going, deciding that this is a problem for the future, not the present, and come to another listening station.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): At this listening station,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's clear that the prisoner is speaking, or addressing at least, Lord Hulda directly.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm giving you what you need and want. You're killing a dragon, but you're not brave. You're sad all the time, you're angry, you're thirsty. I'm giving you a home and wealth and a name. You are giving it to yourself through me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You are promising to come back and help me. You are swearing you will set me free, but you are not. So I'm sending my children to help you, my children.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): being the mushroom men, who are identical to Alden, some kind of a transformation in form from the infection currently, moving through your mathematician friend.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And then some of the final entries in that say, you are bringing 5 friends to help me, they're outside my room right now, they are hearing me, they're coming to my door, and I think they're stepping inside, presumably meaning… you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Having heard that, and been…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know, unsettled, delighted, surprised, unsurprised?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): you come through into the next room, and that's where we ended the last session, in an immense library, with lots and lots of volumes on the shelves, the background image here is a good one, and a sort of a clockwork figure.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That… of just… again, the image is a good one, of just, like, a torso and head that raises its head and looks at you, intently as you enter.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's where we find the party! Will you describe yourselves, and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I would love to hear also, like, what is, for your character, like.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What is the emotional state in this moment? You know this is the last room before the door to the prison at the center.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And… I don't know, like…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Maybe both the micro and the macro. What's your emotional state in this moment, and what's, like, your existential hope?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): To achieve, if and when
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You get back to the real world again.
Tim Sackton: Oh, Charo is a…
Tim Sackton: More than 6 foot tall, lizardfolk man, with greenish scales running along the top of his long snout and over his head, down the spiny back of his neck.
Tim Sackton: Yellow… paler yellow scales along the underside of his jaw, and the bits of, his upper… the…
Tim Sackton: Lower part of his neck that stick out from beneath the worn but functional and well-mended traveler's cloak and tunic and robes that he wears.
Tim Sackton: He is walking cautiously with his wooden shield out, with a design of a stylized bird carved in the front of it.
Tim Sackton: And holding more for…
Tim Sackton: comfort and emotional support, then, because it's a useful weapon. A wand, which you have heard, also produces bird calls.
Tim Sackton: He is carrying very little else, just a few pouches, draped along his belt.
Tim Sackton: And moving… cautiously… Forward, occasionally attempting to stifle a slight cough.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: the…
Tim Sackton: As he looks around the room, Somewhat.
Tim Sackton: Puzzled and,
Tim Sackton: a little bit uncertain as to how he and the rest of the party ended up here. His overwhelming desire is to find his way and get you all, as well, home somehow.
Tim Sackton: Beyond that… he has no real larger goal. He's…
Tim Sackton: problems of Trancorian wizards and fey lords seem… to…
Tim Sackton: Big and significant for him to solve.
Tim Sackton: And so he looks across at you, the four of you.
Tim Sackton: Who he has traveled with, and probably spent nearly every day with for the past year or so.
Tim Sackton: And… Wonders if… The mercenary life is really… the right one.
Tim Sackton: Given where it has brought us.
David S. Kong: kato Min is still wearing his, tall and red.
David S. Kong: Rowe, well-embroidered.
David S. Kong: Long… Silver, golden hair…
David S. Kong: Not tied back at the moment.
David S. Kong: He's looking a little bit worse for the wear, to be very honest. You know, this whole adventure out here in the Feywild…
David S. Kong: he's… For better or for worse, has… Had his… Mode of just, kind of, performing, and…
David S. Kong: doing some mercenary stuff, and working with Tarek, and kinda, like, getting some scores, and… and this journey into this other dimension, and…
David S. Kong: infinite time, and these weird puzzles, and everything that's going on. It's both alienating, but also weirdly a return to something deeper and more ancient, connected to his elven heritage, which, in many ways, he may have been running from, or just kind of ignoring, or not thinking about.
David S. Kong: As he's been engaging in this sort of,
David S. Kong: Human samsara of, like, money and…
David S. Kong: ego, and just living this kind of weird, Tolin lifestyle, and so… He also is feeling…
David S. Kong: Confused and shaken up by this whole experience, but also…
David S. Kong: It's like, it also… like, this all could end really well, and he could all kind of, like, wake up a little bit from what he's been doing and think a little bit more deeply about his life, or not. So we'll see what happens.
David S. Kong: But for now, he's… he's, you know, also glancing at his… at his companions, and…
David S. Kong: More immediately thinking about How do we get out of this… this… current Rubik's Cube.
Mike: Edric is…
Mike: I mean, he's tall, kinda… with his fancy suited breastplate decorated with the Night Queen's symbol and his…
Mike: Yeah.
Mike: Slightly too prominent cheekbones, and jaw, and nose, and kind of slightly… Big. Paul. Strong.
Mike: But not necessarily that,
Mike: you know, definitely not handsome, right? He's, at the micro level, he is… energized by having…
Mike: He feels like that he has a… better… rightly or wrongly.
Mike: He feels like there's an enemy here, and having smashed the mushroom men is feeling energized by that sense of something to fight.
Mike: Which is more his natural habitat than puzzles and mysteries and strange things to do. Longer term, he's…
Mike: More convinced than ever that The Night Queen must have a purpose for him.
Mike: But he is… not sure that this… wandering across the plains… It's really it.
Mike: And he's wondering a little bit.
Mike: How he ended up here.
Mike: And… I'm not really questioning the mercenary life exactly, but… But… thinking… Thoughts that maybe…
Mike: Just maybe he should have a bit more of a purpose.
Mike: And it would keep him out of messes like this.
Kate Sackton: Aveen's armor is still shining bright, she's made it through that last conflict without, directly getting into the…
Kate Sackton: post-combat fray, but she's… It's wearing on her that there have been so many different
Kate Sackton: people to help, and, you know, goals of do-gooding that are just corrupted and confusing, like… first, they were hired by Holda, so they wanted to help Holda, but now they don't want to help Holda, and then they wanted to help the,
Kate Sackton: the elf lord of the Manor, because it seems sort of sad that his party was endlessly ending.
Kate Sackton: But we're not really sure. That's all tied up in all this complexity, and maybe the prisoner-prisoner sounds bad, like, maybe you want to help a prisoner, but then if it's the master of mushroom things that's trying to kill them, then maybe as, Frederick said, it's…
Kate Sackton: an enemy, and…
Kate Sackton: Who she really wants to help is her friends. At this point, we all want to go home.
Kate Sackton: We know we need a key to, like, even get out of this… building, so…
Kate Sackton: We have at least that clear of a purpose, is to help ourselves. And,
Kate Sackton: She's thinking about what sort of healing Charo will need, and, you know, how we can…
Kate Sackton: pull ourselves together and get out of here. And she thinks, you know.
Kate Sackton: I don't know if this society that gave Manicius so much, you know, confidence that they knew what they were doing.
Kate Sackton: Would really be helpful if they were…
Kate Sackton: Less represented by just one crazy mushroom breeder. And,
Kate Sackton: out of his element, mathematician, but I don't know, maybe Tolin has some sort of wise secret societies that need… need volunteers.
Kate Sackton: I don't know, just… it might be nice to be part of something that has some clarity and direction.
Mike: The aimlessness is really wiring on all of us, it sounds.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It makes me so happy. I just… I love it.
Kate Sackton: ourselves.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's the… I… I love the way…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And it's not a thing I expected or was, like, steering towards, but the way that, like, that twilight hour, that sort of second-guessing time.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): which is the moment of Feywild, has become such a part of the, I don't know, the mind state of each of the characters. That's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Makes me really happy.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean, in a tragic, doomed sort of way, but…
Kate Sackton: Project Doom made manifest great.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Can we quick, put our heads together? How do we want to, handle Tarek this session?
Tim Sackton: Usually, the simplest way is to just…
Tim Sackton: Pretend he's there, but… but is tired and not interested in speaking.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Love it. Yeah. Yep, and there's plenty of books here for him to…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Get caught by and reading through, or something like that, too.
David S. Kong: And also, maybe if there's something we think he should be doing, we can raise that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, like, if we need his skills, we can say, hey, Tari, can you…
Kate Sackton: Liberty's locked book.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So here you are, with the… oh, I should say also,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): excuse me, Monistheus, the Drankorian mathematician and mapmaker, is with you also. He's wheezing badly now, and
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Coughing regularly, and just not looking like he's in very good shape, and not saying much.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But… soldiering on forward, too.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And here you are, in the… the library, with the automaton, in one corner,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Stacks of books… Broad, well-lit desks for writing and reading.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A few of the shelves have books that are chained, but mostly they can be… Taken out. Brest, yeah.
David S. Kong: Kato keeps a healthy distance, but, like, totally tries to make eye contact with the automaton, and is, like, trying to stare back at it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It makes eye contact, and… Raises its eyebrows, inquisitively.
David S. Kong: Cato mirrors it and also raises his eyebrows inquisitively.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It raises one, then the other?
David S. Kong: Kato does the same.
David S. Kong: If he's able.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And, shakes its head in a, getting a joke kind of a way.
David S. Kong: Kato also shakes… he continues to, you know, also shakes his head in a getting a joke kind of way.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Alright, the thing, it's gonna keep on mirroring.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Whatever expressions you're making, the best it can.
David S. Kong: No, but I'm mirroring its expressions, so it's… it's whatever it's doing.
Mike: goes forever.
David S. Kong: But wait, is this, like, is this, like, fun? Or is it, like, like, robotic and weird? Or is it, like…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So, there's two things going on.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Which sort of go in different directions. On the one hand.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): there's almost a sense of playfulness, right? Like, there's a very human…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You know, a very sort of, cognizant, you know, like,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): the way that it has a… it has a theory of mind, right? And it's… it has a sense that you are a being, and it's interacting with you, and it's, you know, sort of mirroring. On the other hand.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's unsettling to see that on…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): an automata that's sort of made out of, clockwork and painted porcelain. So, like, the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): you know, there are two individual eyebrows which move around, but the eyeballs themselves are just painted. And that's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Weird.
David S. Kong: Interesting.
David S. Kong: Cato will… Point at it.
Kate Sackton: Aveen is looking around, trying to see if there's anything about the layout of the room that they could… that should be investigated outside of the automaton.
Mike: Where is the actual door?
Kate Sackton: Yeah, like…
Mike: like…
Mike: My impression was we, like, saw the door with the key, right? Did I misunderstand that? Is it, like, somewhere obvious?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, I think it's on the far… it's on the far side of the room, across from where you are, yeah.
Mike: Yes.
Tim Sackton: But there's, like, a door that has a key just… Charwood's gonna walk towards the key. Like, do we see a key in the door?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, exactly. It's a pale blue…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): glass, slightly shiny. It's about… I don't know, 6 inches long, so it's in the door, protruding from it.
Tim Sackton: And… as far as… so, okay, as far as we know…
Tim Sackton: The… Lord EndlesslyEnding said that if we either broke the key, or brought it back to him, the bargain would end.
Tim Sackton: But…
Tim Sackton: it was unclear whether that would actually get us home, except that we had some presumption that Lord Endless the Ending might be willing to do some weird fey magic.
Tim Sackton: Should we help?
Tim Sackton: the…
Tim Sackton: Crazy Dwarven gardener told us that the key would unlock any door, including the front door, so we could plausibly take the key and…
Tim Sackton: Let ourselves out of this house, and then we would be…
Tim Sackton: on the road, but Manestheus and probably Chara would be killed by the road guards.
Tim Sackton: There is… there was some rumor, somewhere, that may… that might be just Charles imagining, or maybe something that was actually told to us, that inside…
Tim Sackton: The prison room, there is a… passage, somehow.
Tim Sackton: A hole big enough for the prisoner to send its children through.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): guests.
Mike: Yep.
Tim Sackton: But… then we have to go into the prison.
Tim Sackton: And this is, as far as we know… all we know.
Tim Sackton: Like, we don't know…
Tim Sackton: We haven't heard any… we don't… there's nothing obvious that I'm missing about what we've learned about the glass key, is that correct?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Correct.
Kate Sackton: Yeah, it got a lot more complicated when you two got infected, because otherwise we were just gonna take the key and…
Kate Sackton: go out to, like, Manicius New, where there were other portals back to Kaldar, and just travel the Feywild.
Kate Sackton: to, like, some… freely access… freely accessible portal home, and leave… behind us.
Tim Sackton: And our… our understanding, although it might be wrong, is if we take the key.
Tim Sackton: But don't destroy it, or give it to…
Tim Sackton: Lord, endlessly ending, plausibly, things just continue as they are.
Tim Sackton: Or, if we remove the key from the door, The bargain ends.
Tim Sackton: Do we know?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think that you know, he said that in…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In order for the bargain to end, he would need to destroy the key, suggesting that removing it from the door doesn't
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like you said, doesn't change the status quo.
Mike: So, we have to… we have to bring it back to him, but now we can't bring it back to him, because…
Mike: child.
Mike: And the SDs will be killed by the guards, because they smell bad.
Tim Sackton: Except… Except Charo can turn into a spider and hide.
Mike: Regardless.
Tim Sackton: But…
Mike: Don't you, Rev.
Tim Sackton: Maybe.
Tim Sackton: That doesn't help Manestius.
Kate Sackton: I mean.
Mike: And…
Kate Sackton: The sis can hang out, like, right in the front hallway.
Kate Sackton: Possibly if we turn Lord Hulda into some…
Kate Sackton: super grateful, super being, and get him to help us with our sick friends problem, too, in addition to our getting home problem. And I'm not exactly sure how much you can catch.
Mike: Warren Halta's and all of the people causing the illness.
Kate Sackton: Sorry, I didn't say… I meant to say Lord Endless.
Tim Sackton: Endlessly ending.
Tim Sackton: So, while everybody else is investigating the library, and…
Tim Sackton: and talk… and mirroring the automaton. Char was gonna sit down in front of the door with the key.
Tim Sackton: He's gonna take out his flute.
Tim Sackton: And he's gonna begin… or his wand, and he's gonna just begin a sort of low loon call, and he is going to use Augury to ask
Tim Sackton: The ancestors is ancestors.
Tim Sackton: If… We take this key and leave.
Tim Sackton: And bring it to Lord Endlessly Ending.
Tim Sackton: Is that bad or good?
Tim Sackton: This takes 10 minutes, so you can go around and figure out everybody else's actions and resolve other things while you think.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Good, I'm gonna ponder on that one.
Kate Sackton: 18… Sends a… Quiet, whispered message.
Kate Sackton: To be out of the automaton's hearing, because she doesn't know how good its hearing is. To say, are we avoiding…
Kate Sackton: Talking to that thing, or…
David S. Kong: I was role-playing with it still, then we, so I'm just gonna.
Kate Sackton: Yeah, but I guess I'm sort of whispering to you, are you never gonna talk to it because you think that's a bad idea, or can we talk to it now?
David S. Kong: Literally, I was pointing at it, I wanted to see if it was gonna point, and then other people started roleplaying, which is great, so I'm still… I still want to continue doing the thing, the thing, yes.
Kate Sackton: But I'm asking you in your mind, are you just.
David S. Kong: Yes, good, no, I'm gonna, I'm gonna talk to it, yes.
Kate Sackton: Oh, you're gonna talk to it, talk to it.
David S. Kong: Just keep this.
Kate Sackton: Those things, okay.
David S. Kong: No, no, no, no. Well, we're gonna get there.
Kate Sackton: Okay.
David S. Kong: So I pointed.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It smiles back at you, and then its face sort of falls, and it looks down to where its arms are not.
David S. Kong: And then, Kato goes like this.
David S. Kong: Like this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It… it shakes its head.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It nods its head.
David S. Kong: Wow.
David S. Kong: Kato genuinely likes this entity. Kato's like, what happened to your arms?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They were never built.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think my creators…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know if they thought I would get too much trouble if I had them.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Or if they just didn't think they would be necessary. But it's a terrible inconvenience.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I have an itch on my nose.
David S. Kong: Cato goes over…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I… I… I don't, actually. It's… it's humor, you see, I'm… I'm still working on it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sorry.
David S. Kong: No,
David S. Kong: I'm an elf. I don't get all the jokes, either. I was just trying to be helpful if you actually did have an itch, but I'm glad that you don't.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's been a long time since I've seen an elf. In fact, this may be the longest conversation that I've had in several centuries.
David S. Kong: Really? When's the last time you saw an elf?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean, centuries, I don't know exactly. A very, very long, terribly long time.
David S. Kong: Well, how do you even keep track of time in here?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's the trouble, isn't it? That's the trouble. The…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The books, some of them, the ones that haven't been preserved magically, the paper ages slightly, and I listen for the aging of the paper. I pay very close attention to everything that's in the books, you see.
David S. Kong: You can tell how much time has passed by listening to the aging of the paper.
David S. Kong: Wow.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like I said, I pay very close attention.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And it stares uncannily and unsettlingly into your eyes.
David S. Kong: What else do you notice? What are the things you pay attention to most?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I was designed… I was created as a synthesizer of research and information.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I've read all of the contents of the library, and I help the researchers find what they need. And…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And… And because it's been a long time since those services have been needed.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I've been writing my own books about the people that I meet.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I listen very carefully to everything in the pages, and everything I hear and see.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And I write a story about who you are.
David S. Kong: That is amazing. Who were the last people that you met before us?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): you hear the sound of… of worrying and clicking as the computation begins to unfold. And actually, I want to pause there and go over, to Tarek, if there's… if there's anything that…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That you wouldn't do.
Tim Sackton: You mean a drink?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, yeah, sorry, sorry, Edric, yeah.
Mike: Patrick has really… Not.
Mike: He's kind of pacing around.
Mike: He kinda… he keeps looking at the door like he just kinda wants to go through and confront the prisoner.
Mike: But he's not quite ready to do that, especially because it seems like the rest of the party is probably not on board with that. So he keeps kind of walking towards the door and staring at it, then walking back. He's not… the Tomadon's freaking about, he's not that interested in books. Is there anything else in the room other than books, a door, and automatons?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean, there's more books. There's… you notice there are…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's one shelf which is empty, and there's a note written on it.
Mike: What does it say?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It says, the Zaruka call is currently out for circulation by special dispensation.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's a… that's a little Easter egg for… for the deep readers of Telgarverse.
David S. Kong: Nice.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But no, the real answer is no, it's… I mean, it's books, shelves, scratch paper, pens,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But it's… It's very much a library.
Kate Sackton: Are there other doors? We came in a door, and then there's the door we're contemplating. Is this one of those three-door rooms?
Kate Sackton: Is there, like, another door that we're…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Let me think about that for just a sec.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So, yes, this does happen to be a 3-door room, and the door to the 27th room, that is the door to the prison room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): is on an exterior face. In other words, it's on a wall where you have not seen a door on any other wall that you've been to.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But otherwise, it's the normal number of exits off this room.
Kate Sackton: So, Evie insists to Charo.
Kate Sackton: Do you want to keep an eye on both the other doors, just because we don't know what could come through them?
Tim Sackton: Charles is right still in the middle, I presume, of his…
Kate Sackton: Sorry, not Charo.
Kate Sackton: Hedrick.
Mike: Yeah? I mean, Etrick's happy to keep watch.
David S. Kong: How does the automaton respond?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Utahman Han says, some time ago.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's difficult to judge the passage of time in increments smaller than about 50 or 60 years, because of the slow pace of the change in the pages themselves.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But sometime relatively recently, there was a human woman who came through who must have been a member of the order.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Who stopped to talk to me for… for just a moment.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She, she wanted me to find a book for her.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This one, in fact, she left it here. This is part of the frustration of not having arms or legs. I can't reshelve the books. And he nods towards a book that's been left on the desk in front of him.
David S. Kong: Would you like me to…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I would appreciate that. It's the third row back, the second shelf on the left, Second from the bottom.
Tim Sackton: is the book.
Kate Sackton: Why did she want it?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's called Allegories for the Initiated. It's a collection of, stories…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Meant for members of the Order.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Which…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): reveal the deep secrets of the order, if you know what they mean, which doesn't make sense to me, because if you already know what they mean, why do you need a book to read about what they mean? Allegories for the initiated. As you page through it, it reads almost as a collection of, like, short fairy tales.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Or… or riddles. There's one that says, what is a mind in a mindless thing? If a parrot might mimic speech so perfectly that a person is fooled.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): How do you know whether it's a parrot or a person?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's another which is about a man who's, can have children, but none of the children that he has can have children, and his
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Obsessed with carrying on the family line, and relentlessly sleeps with more and more people until at last he, exhausts himself and dies.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There, I mean, it… The… There's a…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's another which is a bet about,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Two wizards who had a bet that hedgehogs could be made to kill and transformed into vicious animals, and then a series of sort of horrific,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Experiments and activities that induced small, cute animals to be terrible.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's one about a kingdom of storytellers, in which the best story becomes fact.
Kate Sackton: Did she… did she react to reading this book in a way that you could understand?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, she flipped through a few of these pages and then… left. I'm not…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm not sure she understood what it was saying.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Or if it… I couldn't tell you.
Kate Sackton: Did… did she… which way did she leave?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh, through the… through the door. And he nods towards the door to the prisoner.
David S. Kong: How do we get in there?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Turn the key and step through.
David S. Kong: Is there a key in the door?
Mike: Yes.
David S. Kong: Oh, shit.
Kate Sackton: We understand that we can use this key also to get
Kate Sackton: To unlock the front door of this building.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He nods thoughtfully, indeed. You could take it with you and let yourself out.
Kate Sackton: You're not aware of any detrimental effect on the mission of the imprisonment.
Kate Sackton: From this course as often.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Its eyes flip back and forth rapidly, as if scanning through many, many pages.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And it says, I have nothing in the records here that suggests that that would not go well.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And I see some references that suggest it's happened in the past, and then been brought back again.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Which makes me think it's an achievable course of action.
Kate Sackton: Encouraging.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): How else can I be of assistance in your research?
David S. Kong: Share more about the prisoner.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No.
David S. Kong: Why not?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I've been instructed not to.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): As one of the conditions of my operation.
Kate Sackton: Are there any recent writings from members of the order since the…
Kate Sackton: Magically fungal infestation of this building that has led to mushroom people.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, that appears to have happened after the order relinquished control of the building.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Some time ago, they all left, and the infection became bad.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): After that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Or at least, it was after they all left that I first noticed the mushroom men.
Kate Sackton: Do the Mushroom Men read your books?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I've never been able to talk to them, I…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know if they can see me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It says that almost… Questioningly, as if it's saying a thing it knows doesn't make sense.
Kate Sackton: But you have not observed them take books off the shelves and read them without your guidance.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Correct, they always seem to move with purpose out of this room.
Kate Sackton: Do they freely come in and out of that door?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, they come out once from the central room and never return again.
David S. Kong: Where's the central room that they come out of?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Meaning the prison room behind the key.
David S. Kong: Oh, shit, the Mushroom men come out of that room. How many mushroom men have come out of that room?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I would estimate… Roughly two-thirds of all who enter So…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And it runs through in its head as if doing mental calculation.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Approximately 112.
Mike: Two-thirds of all who enter… the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): the prism.
David S. Kong: come out as Mushroom men?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Correct.
David S. Kong: What happens to the ones that do not?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The others do not emerge.
David S. Kong: How many total have gone in that room?
David S. Kong: the exact number?
Kate Sackton: 170…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 112 times 1.5.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What's up?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 158, something like that?
David S. Kong: It gives us an exact number, right?
Kate Sackton: Yes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It doesn't say something like that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Thank you.
David S. Kong: Alright, let's roll with 168.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Good.
David S. Kong: And, do you know what causes the ones…
David S. Kong: Do you know what differentiates those that
David S. Kong: become the Mushroom Man vs. Do not.
David S. Kong: Is there any assessment that you can conclude based on those that, are going into the room? Which…
David S. Kong: Or what characteristics of those that go into the room lead them to become Mushroom men versus not?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's difficult to say, however… Those who become the Mushroom Men…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): To me, seem to be the ones who are untrustworthy.
David S. Kong: Untrustworthy by your… In your, in your perspective?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I am a keen judge of character.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Hmm.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Interesting.
David S. Kong: And you don't know what happens to… or the… what causes them to be turned into… do you know what happens, what causes them to be turned into Mushroom men?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That I do not.
David S. Kong: When did the order begin research… Begin this mushroom research?
David S. Kong: And why?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It will take some time to formulate an answer to that question.
Mike: Gesture at Taterman.
Mike: Are we trustworthy? Is… is this 5L trustworthy?
David S. Kong: Is what?
Mike: Are you trustworthy?
Mike: You're asking the automatons. No, no, the automaton.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): it… it snaps back again and says,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Hang on, what does it say exactly?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes, though he is not yet certain that he believes himself to be.
David S. Kong: Wait, sorry, Edric asks.
Mike: I asked that time and thought if you were trustworthy.
David S. Kong: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And the automaton said, yes, but you are not sure that you believe that you are.
David S. Kong: Oh, interesting.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Wow, deep.
David S. Kong: Hmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Anything else may I be of assistance in your research?
David S. Kong: Yeah, any advice, cause we're gonna go in there, and so, do you have any advice for us about, so…
David S. Kong: Any tips, again, based on your analysis of those that have come and gone and become Mushroom men and not become Mushroom men.
David S. Kong: Do you have any advice for us, so as we can, minimize or maximize the likelihood that we do not become mushroommen? Any advice?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Because all mushroom men have come back out of the store, I hypothesize that if there is a different exit, you should take it in order not to become a mushroom man.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No one who's come back out that door has not been a mushroom man.
David S. Kong: Oh, wow, so… once we go in, we're never gonna see you again, unless we become Mushroom men.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I will remember you.
David S. Kong: Hato, like, pauses genuinely for a moment.
David S. Kong: You might be the best friend I've ever had.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I got to set to the side.
Kate Sackton: Estimous!
Kate Sackton: We didn't hear that.
Tim Sackton: At this point, I think Park gives Cato Man a… elbow.
David S. Kong: You guys are like, -oh, did I say that out loud?
Tim Sackton: Maybe he tries to steal something.
David S. Kong: I mean, except you guys, of course.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This is a good moment for the Agri to come back, and… and I'll…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'll fudge the black and whiteness of the Agri a little bit, say.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What it tells you is that going through the door is not automatically, whoa. It's complicated. It doesn't mean everything will be sunshine and roses.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But it's not…
Tim Sackton: I asked if I'd take the key, Bring it back to Lord
Tim Sackton: ending. Will that be good or bad?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): it's the same response. It's not,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's not bad. It is… it's more complicated than just good or bad, but it's not… Bad.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): there's danger attendant to it, but I think you knew that already, and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Making your way back while infected.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): How else may I be of assistance in your research?
David S. Kong: Kato looks around. Anything else we need to know before we just go in there?
David S. Kong: Who made the prison?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The erythromos lamparum built the structure which surrounds the prism.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The exact records of the constructor of the original prison are not found in my archives. However, I hypothesize that it was an early member of this order.
David S. Kong: Do you know the purpose for which the, this was built?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): While I do not have the exact purpose for which this was built, I have a research suggestion for you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): On pages 66 to 67,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): of the third shelf on the second row, second book from the left, called On the Science and Possibilities of Soul Bindery.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And I invite you to read.
David S. Kong: Kato gets the book. What's written on those pages?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It is an ancient tome called On the Science and Possibilities of Soul Bindery, and
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What it seems to suggest is that
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Is a possibility which, as you read it, you find viscerally revolting.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The notion that the energy contained within a soul can be tapped and used, and it enthusiastically hypothesizes on the various uses of the energy of a bound soul.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That you could bind a soul to a phylactery to create a lick form.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But the author seems to think that even that application is still basic in terms of what's possible.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He says on one page, one can drink from a stream, but the wise man builds a water wheel and binds the force of moving water to use.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Such a phylactery is like a millstone set to the water of souls useful, but only the barest beginning of the possible. Imagine, for example, a golem or automata powered by such mode of force. Imagine, for example, anything possible powered by a captive soul.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And it's motion trying to move elsewhere, but forever prevented from doing so.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The automaton pipes up and says,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's one other note in this book that I think may be applicable to the exit from the inside of the room. Check page 225.
David S. Kong: Of the same book.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 225 in the same book is a long passage on what the, the author is talking about entities that are soul hoarders, and speaking of them incredibly disparagingly, collectors of souls who don't put them to use.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): doing things.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's one passage which says, a soul hoarder is like the great worm whose horde lust has become its master.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Whether it be the spice-scented timbers of Eloria, or the gold-wrought statues through which the forest people wish to fashion a new god, the worm sits on its treasure neither using nor destroying it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And it goes on to say, Eucostus relates a story on a scroll since destroyed, that Yendela once met a sojourner who had themself escaped from such a soul horde.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The door to which sits inside a tree root beyond the setting sun. Leaving aside the veracity of such a story, I will comment merely on the absurdity and waste that such fecundity of soul energy should sit idle.
David S. Kong: Kano Min's like, who wrote this book? He looks at the cover. Who's the author of the book?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): some erythromosome param person centuries ago.
David S. Kong: What's the relationship between the author of this book and the creation of this whole, place that we are in?
David S. Kong: And by the way, what's her name?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm a research assistant.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I was never given a name.
David S. Kong: Would you like a name?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes.
David S. Kong: What would you like your name to be?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'll have to process that request.
David S. Kong: Here's my one request to you. Before we go in that door, make sure that you let us know what you want your name to be.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I will.
David S. Kong: Great.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And he looks thoughtfully off into the distance.
David S. Kong: But again, what's the relationship between the author of this book and the creation of this place?
Kate Sackton: If I… may…
Kate Sackton: I think that the research assistant was pointing us to the motivation for creating a prison like this.
Kate Sackton: Perhaps being too… Harness Soul Power as one puts a hydroelectric dam in a… Waterway.
David S. Kong: Yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This is my guess at the purpose.
Kate Sackton: If our perspective on that is, yay soul energy, then we probably want to keep this factory running.
Kate Sackton: If our perspective on this is… poor trapped soul.
Kate Sackton: Then maybe the prisoner is just…
Kate Sackton: A poor, trapped soul that has been forced to create soul energy for…
Kate Sackton: Centuries, and… sure, he's made some mushroom men trying to escape, but…
Kate Sackton: He's been trapped for a long time for somebody else's gain.
Kate Sackton: Maybe that's kind of reasonable?
Kate Sackton: I don't know, how do we feel about this…
David S. Kong: Well, what's… what's the Soul Energy, research assistant, whose name, hopefully, you will come up with shortly?
David S. Kong: What do you think is the, use of the energy that's coming out of this whole system?
David S. Kong: The soul energy.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I do not have that information.
Mike: Idris kind of, like, scratched his head, like, wait, this doesn't make any sense.
Mike: You're saying that, like… You're harvesting the energy from souls?
Mike: Is that what we think is happening here?
Mike: Like, like a necromancer.
Mike: Like, the worst thing in the world.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All progress requires sacrifice.
Mike: No, that's the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
Mike: Wait, this is, like, taking people's souls? Is that what we think is happening?
Kate Sackton: I don't know if we think it's many people's souls.
David S. Kong: I think it's just one person's soul, or one person's soul.
Kate Sackton: Just the prisoner's soul.
David S. Kong: Yeah.
Kate Sackton: Is such a… such a powerful soul that it's been used for power for all this time.
David S. Kong: But to power what?
Kate Sackton: Who knows?
Mike: One or many, it's all the same.
Mike: The crime isn't better for being only one.
Kate Sackton: Well, Edric… What would you think of a soul?
Kate Sackton: That was being… Trapped.
Kate Sackton: Or used for power, or whatever.
Kate Sackton: Ben… Harming others as a way to try to help free itself.
Kate Sackton: It's not… two bads make it good, but it's not bad for no reason.
David S. Kong: What do we know about this prisoner?
David S. Kong: Do we know anything about this prisoner?
Kate Sackton: I mean, there was a whole… Passage about appreciating souls.
Kate Sackton: A prisoner might be a soul hoarder.
David S. Kong: The prisoner is a soul hoarder? I thought it was the… that the order is hoarding this one particular soul, at least.
David S. Kong: I mean, this book is all about one of the founders of this whole order, talking about how great it is to hoard souls.
Kate Sackton: No, he talks about how terrible it is to hoard souls.
David S. Kong: Or to use souls.
Kate Sackton: Yes, absolutely.
Mike: works.
David S. Kong: Or, like, animating that golem.
Mike: But using a soul?
David S. Kong: Seems like it. Seems like what… that's what these people are doing. What is that?
Mike: hold on a second, actually, my character's chic.
Mike: I have not opened my cash sheet.
Mike: In a while.
Mike: Give me one second.
Kate Sackton: Check on Edric's, deep theological knowledge.
Mike: Nope. Detection of… Necromancy.
David S. Kong: Schwartz, Kato will, as the example, what's the… we'll ask the RA,
David S. Kong: How deep and integrated within the founding and operation of the order
David S. Kong: Is this idea of using souls to do things, and has the order used souls to do things in the past, and what kind of things?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I have two additional sources on that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In one, an early member of the Order Laments the fact that they're…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Deceased enemies can be brought back again, and wishes instead for some way to have annihilated them wholly and completely that could never be returned.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In the second, Another member of the order.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Speaks of the possibility of using this force to extend one's lifespan indefinitely.
David S. Kong: Did anybody succeed?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's beyond the scope of information that I have access to.
Mike: People who succeed at that are called glitches, they're terrible, you have to destroy them.
Mike: What is wrong with all you people?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All progress requires sacrifice.
Mike: So this is an order of necromancers.
Kate Sackton: I mean, I believe she had a record of one.
Kate Sackton: I don't know if that means it's an order of necromancers.
Mike: Is Menestis around?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, menest these is sort of slumped over a table nearby.
Mike: AJ's gonna go, like, Try and pull him up and, like, see how he's doing.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He's unsteady on his feet, and wobbly, and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It takes him a minute for his eyes to focus on your face.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep, yep.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): we… What are we… where, what are we doing?
Mike: They told me it's a hundred years ago.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): later.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What?
Mike: Is your interested order… destroy souls?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't have the first clue what you're talking about. Does my order…
Mike: That's what this automata over here said.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Listen… A lot of wizards did a lot of weird shit, right?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You saw the fungus, lady.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's not my department.
Mike: She seemed to be telling the truth.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You're really insane.
Mike: See, like…
Mike: 21.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): yeah. Yeah. It… it… he…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You're not hearing from him a denial that this is one of the things that they do or did.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sure. But certainly a denial that he knew anything about it. He's still very much convinced and entirely convicted by the idea of policing the boundaries between worlds in order to keep Talgar safe.
Tim Sackton: Charles will slowly stand up from where he's been sitting by the door.
Tim Sackton: In thought or meditation, and walk over.
Tim Sackton: Having been half-listening to the conversation.
Tim Sackton: And he will say.
Tim Sackton: It seems to me… Like… Our job, our… Hope, or arm.
Tim Sackton: Beth's job here is not to…
Tim Sackton: Try and police the evident sins of some long-dead order.
Tim Sackton: But… To find a way to get ourselves home.
Tim Sackton: And it seems like we have only two choices.
Tim Sackton: take the key, and bring it back to Lord Endlessly Ending.
Tim Sackton: Or… Enter the room and see what happens.
Tim Sackton: My ancestors have told me It is at least not unequivocally bad if we pursue the…
Tim Sackton: Bring the key to Lord's Endlessly ending.
Tim Sackton: Though, it would require navigating the road guards.
Tim Sackton: If Monistleus feels that this is… A challenge that is…
Tim Sackton: too difficult in his current state, and wishes to step into the room, I don't think we should stop him.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This is back to being slumped over the table again, so he has no comment on this. He's sorta out of it. Look at me in my face.
Tim Sackton: I do not know.
Tim Sackton: That there is a… clear way home, even if we do that. We are relying on…
Tim Sackton: The generosity of the Fae?
David S. Kong: In which case?
Tim Sackton: Whereas we know there is another accent on the other side of the door.
David S. Kong: Isn't anybody else just curious about what's on the other side of that door?
Tim Sackton: No.
David S. Kong: I am.
Mike: I…
Tim Sackton: Charo smiles and, like, like, looks down at Kato in a sort of toothy grin, just kind of nods, like…
Tim Sackton: Yes, obviously, that goes without saying. I'm sure Tarek is also jumping at the bit to get in there.
Tim Sackton: Hello!
David S. Kong: and Park are definitely, like… I mean, what's the harm in just checking it out?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The, at that, the reference assistant, chuckles a little bit, and says, more evidence that curiosity is, indeed.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): An uncurable addiction.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And you're reminded of the book you came across that made that same argument.
Tim Sackton: You know, the harm is that we turn into mushroom people.
David S. Kong: Yeah, but…
David S. Kong: RA said it himself, or themselves. It's like a… you know, it's like a… it's like a… what percent?
Kate Sackton: 6%?
Tim Sackton: Thirds?
Kate Sackton: dance?
David S. Kong: 3rd.
Kate Sackton: out of the… Both of us?
Mike: Did any groups go in?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No groups have entered.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It has always been one at a time, one after another.
David S. Kong: The door only allows one at a time?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, rather, it is the case that not more than one person has been in the room at the time… at a time.
David S. Kong: Oh, this is the first time there's been more than one person.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh, yes.
David S. Kong: Wow, that's cool.
Mike: I must say, I was prepared to…
Mike: Charge in that room and attempt to kill whatever monster was on the other side.
Mike: But now, I'm not so sure it's not…
Mike: An innocent, or at least a victim.
Mike: And I do not… Know what to do.
Kate Sackton: Well, if we want more information on… Monster Vic- or victim.
Kate Sackton: I think we have to go through the door to get it.
Mike: True.
David S. Kong: Let's put it this way.
David S. Kong: If we take the key, And we want to bring it back to Endlessly Ending.
David S. Kong: We can do that.
David S. Kong: But we know, already.
David S. Kong: all of that part. It's like just going backwards and doing the stuff that we already did.
David S. Kong: Going into the door is the new thing that we don't know what will happen.
David S. Kong: Right?
David S. Kong: That makes sense to everybody here, right? And Tarek is like, Obviously.
Mike: So…
Mike: I have a spell, Detect Evil and Good, which detects undead, but I don't really want to think there's any undead here.
Mike: I want to try and, like, meditate, pray to the Night Queen, and see if I can use that spell to sense any hint of necromantic energy anywhere.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Fascinating question. Okay, I'm gonna look up the spell description while…
Mike: It's not technically what the spell does. It detects Fae or undead, technically.
Mike: But I'm gonna try and pray to the Night Queen to let me know.
Mike: If there's any… if there's any necromancy here.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's gonna take me a minute to… Yeah. That's fine.
Mike: Take your time.
Kate Sackton: Did I heal anybody? Does anybody need healing?
Mike: Em… Doesn't our companion Misties look kinda bad? But I guess you would need a cure disease.
Mike: to help them.
Kate Sackton: Yeah, I don't have any…
Tim Sackton: I mean, I have lesser restoration, but I'm…
Tim Sackton: I have so few second-level slots, I'm… saving it.
Kate Sackton: You think you could lesser restoration yourself so that you're not contaminated?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You could definitely make a…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know, whatever check you think is appropriate, if you want to take a guess at that one.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): medicine? Maybe? Arcana, maybe?
Tim Sackton: That's a 22? Oh no, wait, that's an 8.
Tim Sackton: Why does the… the die says 18, why does it say an 8?
Kate Sackton: This is 4.
Kate Sackton: This is what it looked like on my screen.
Tim Sackton: Mine said, on my screen, it looked like 18. Anyway, it's an 8, so I probably don't know.
Tim Sackton: That's weird.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, you can re-roll if you want.
Tim Sackton: Where did that look like?
Tim Sackton: That's a 15, so that's a 19.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With a 19.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): you are… pretty confident that Lester Restoration would resolve your symptoms, but you are not at all confident
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean, ministheus at this point is sort of drifting in and out of consciousness, and it's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He seems pretty far gone.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So it seems unlikely.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That that would be enough.
Tim Sackton: So… I could just go.
Tim Sackton: And… I believe he'll be killed by the road guards.
Tim Sackton: He has no way of hiding.
Tim Sackton: If we're gonna leave, The best we can do is…
Tim Sackton: send him into the room, or leave him here so he can go into the room after we exit. Or maybe…
Tim Sackton: Wait, we can't leave this room without him, can we?
Tim Sackton: Unless we kill him.
Mike: what…
Tim Sackton: Not sure Char was prepared to kill him.
Mike: Why can't we leave this room at that time?
Kate Sackton: Because we have to do everything together, because of the way the building works.
David S. Kong: I…
Kate Sackton: If he went through the door.
Kate Sackton: I don't know if we have to go through the door if he goes through the door.
Tim Sackton: True.
Kate Sackton: different door.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Point?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Mike, detect good and evil.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think that this does, like.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In your prayer, like, you get a sense, not just if there are aberrations or undead.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But also, if there's a place or an object that's been consecrated or desecrated, And I think…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think there is a clear and unambiguous sense of wrongness that you have. It comes off that book, that you were looking at. It comes off of…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It comes off of the, the research assistant.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's not…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's not a desecration in the sense that someone has come in and made a pure and beautiful thing into something awful, or, you know, infected it with some sort of an awfulness, as much as
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): you have a really clear sense. In your attunement to the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): understanding and flow of the Night Queen and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): the rightness of how living and dying works in the universe. These are things that are against that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And it's… clear to you.
Kate Sackton: Park's clock.
David S. Kong: Let's go see what's on the other side of the door!
Mike: Yeah, no, so… Ajric, we'll start out.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Not in the clock, yeah.
Mike: Egypt will… Sort of come out of his…
Mike: his prayer, and kind of what Garad would say.
Mike: We have to go through.
Mike: that door.
David S. Kong: We kill what's on the other side.
Mike: We free it.
David S. Kong: Ugh.
Mike: This place is wrong.
David S. Kong: Tato kind of.
Mike: Or die trying, I guess.
David S. Kong: Kato stands in front of the automaton, like, blocking, each view of the automaton, as…
Mike: That'd be sad.
David S. Kong: Yeah, this message wrong. He's like, hmm, I agree.
Mike: If…
Tim Sackton: If we want to free it, shouldn't we take the key to endlessly ending?
Mike: Maybe that's better?
Mike: You're the planners, folks.
Mike: The moral clarity, though, is free it.
David S. Kong: I'm cool with that. Is that… but don't… we don't have… don't we… we… freeing it is not going in the door, or freeing it is going in the door? Somebody help me with this.
Tim Sackton: We don't really know.
Mike: We don't really know.
Kate Sackton: Appropriate either way.
Mike: Possibly either one would be a possibility.
Mike: for freeing it, we're not… we don't know… I guess explosively. We don't know very clearly what's happening here.
Kate Sackton: It feels like there might be two flavors of freeing it.
Mike: Yeah.
Kate Sackton: like… Freeing it in a letting endlessly ending…
Kate Sackton: have most agency, and we're just sort of bystanders who quickly just hand something off and hope that the side effect of
Kate Sackton: Freeing the prisoner happens, and we'll never really know.
Kate Sackton: Or we go try to free the prisoner and help the prisoner actively free the prisoner's self, which probably also side effect benefits endlessly ending. I don't know if I… either one gets us home more, surely. I think the prisoner would be likely to be more grateful than Endlessly ending, being…
Kate Sackton: A prisoner versus a fae.
David S. Kong: All I'm saying is, we're already here, there's a key in the door.
David S. Kong: All we have to do is open the door and go inside, and then we can do the freaking thing, we can make a better judgment, let's go inside.
Kate Sackton: Alright, you don't want to do the boring freeing thing, you want to do the mysterious freeing thing. Okay.
David S. Kong: I'm just saying that there's a door that we have been trying really fucking hard to find, and we're here, and there's a key inside, and it's just… like, Kato and Tarek are just like, like, what, why, what is this, what's the…
Mike: Adriac looks at you and says, come on, let's go, what are we waiting for?
Kate Sackton: What do you think, Cheryl?
Tim Sackton: The power will acquiesce.
Tim Sackton: The risk…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): or just the…
Tim Sackton: Everybody wants to go that way.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Cox says head to the side and says, How else may I be of assistance in your research?
Mike: Could you please destroy all the research about these terrible things?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Unfortunately, I was designed without arms, hands, or legs, and I'm unable to fulfill that request.
Tim Sackton: Ciao!
Mike: Can you lie the next time somebody comes here asking about these terrible things, and tell them nothing?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He looks long and deeply into your eyes, like making eye contact in a way that seems to see through you, and says.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I do not think anyone else will be coming here.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With a little bit of wistfulness in his voice.
David S. Kong: How do you know that?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think it will be lonely for a long time.
David S. Kong: Why do you think that?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I see it in your eyes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, and he looks from one to the other of you.
David S. Kong: You think we're gonna destroy this place, yeah.
Tim Sackton: Charo will cast Laceration on himself, and then… who's… who has the book that, the Soulbinding book.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's on the table next to you.
Tim Sackton: Char will pick this up and hold it out.
Tim Sackton: to Edric, and say.
Tim Sackton: I normally don't concern such things, but for you, and cast, produce flame, and light it on fire.
Mike: Egypt will, like, touch his holy symbol in gratitude. Does it burn?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It burns, yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Because who would destroy it? This is an artifact of, like, priceless utility!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's now gone from the world.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Some people just don't believe that progress involves sacrifice.
David S. Kong: Book burners?
Tim Sackton: Let's go!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The research assistant says.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): May I tell you your stories? Before you go?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think I will not have others to talk to for a very long time.
David S. Kong: Can we bring it with us?
David S. Kong: Do you wanna come with us?
Kate Sackton: Looks heavy.
Mike: Let's swim…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like, and then the other.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's… I mean, it's heavy, it's probably a good…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 45 or 50 pounds worth of… stuff.
Mike: It's kinda heavy.
Tim Sackton: I can't even carry that. It's not heavy.
David S. Kong: Do you want to come with us? We can bring you with us.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know if I'm able to.
David S. Kong: Will you let us try?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes, I am not able to want to leave.
David S. Kong: You are not able to want to leave.
David S. Kong: If you were out… If you were not here, would you… Would you be happy?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I know that I'm not happy, alone by myself. I've read all of these books already.
David S. Kong: Kato looks at everybody.
David S. Kong: He's 45 pounds. Let's bring him with us!
David S. Kong: What's your name now? Have you figured it out yet?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I would like my name to be Array.
Tim Sackton: ladder and drank corian.
David S. Kong: Shut up, does it really?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Does it really?
Mike: No, just to figure that out.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's awesome, though. Yeah, I love it.
Kate Sackton: Hooray.
David S. Kong: You're coming with us. Let's go.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): May I tell you the stories before we go?
David S. Kong: Oh, please, yeah. You could tell us our story.
Mike: Yes, yes.
David S. Kong: That tells the story, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Mike: Speak away.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Who would like to hear their story first?
Mike: I would.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Edric.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I will tell you a story about trustworthy friends.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Once upon a time, there was an old woman dressed all in black, who was the godmother to the sun, and to every sun that crossed the sky every day.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Whether waking or dreaming.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No one who saw her face could remember or explain what it was they had seen, so they called it Shadow.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She did not live in a house.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But sat beside the one gate
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Which sits in the fence that divides night from day, the twilight gate that keeps the two apart from each other.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Each time a bright sun was born, it passed through the world, and over the village, and through the gate into the darkness to the place where all stars go after they've gone out, and each time the old woman would open the gate and gently greet her son by its name as it went through.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Until one day, a boy in the village fell in love with the sons that went by.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All day long he watched them, and cried when they passed beyond his sight.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So he fashioned a net at the end of a tall pole, and caught the sun as it passed, and put it in a box just for himself, not knowing that the old woman was waiting for her child at the gate that divides night from day.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What is the purpose of a trustworthy friend under that twilight sky?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): How would one be a friend to the old woman, and to the son, and to the boy?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Whose story is next?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Kato Min.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I will tell you a story about reason and consequence and purpose.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Once upon a time.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There was a seed which lived at a tree with all the other seeds born in that same season.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They all lived together in happiness. They learned to sing, and to speak, and to dance together, and to tell the story of their tree, until one day, a great wind came.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And Little Seed and all of his brothers and sisters blew out into the world.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Seasons turned, but he stayed a seed, and blew from one place to the next, because he was not sure where he should be planted.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sometimes, he yearned to go back home.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But he came to believe that the path home was closed to him, and so he never tried to take it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And the strangest thing was, when he saw his siblings, and the trees that had grown from seasons past, they could not recognize that he was still a seed.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sometimes he would see his sibling seeds from past, and visit a while, and see what they had grown to become, but that seed never found its reason or consequence or purpose, and it went on drifting through the air, searching for a place to plant.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Until it came to a twilight sky.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Where did it find to plant?
David S. Kong: Where?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Whose story is next?
David S. Kong: Wait, wait.
David S. Kong: Alright. Sorry, the stories are… what are those… what are those stories about, related to the person you're telling them to?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I listened very carefully.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): To everything in all of these pages, and everything that I've ever heard and ever seen, and everything that I can ever hear or see inside each of you, and I tell you a story about who you are.
David S. Kong: That's a story about who we are based on everything that you know about all the books in here, plus us.
David S. Kong: Cool.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Whose story is next?
Kate Sackton: Will you tell me my story, please?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Aveen, I will tell you a story about light and joy and well-being and doing good.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Once upon a time, a forester planted a forest.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Row after row of saplings grew up straight and strong and upright and beautiful.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The forester would walk down the rows of trees and sigh with contentment, because everything was right and in its rightful place.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): When the tree lost a branch in the storm, she would bandage it. When another needed healing, she would heal it and help them grow strong again. And when they grew sad at the thought of one day being cut down, she would help them remember that all things which have a beginning have an ending.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But a storm that started on a distant ocean… Slivered the leaves with hail.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And burned the branches with lightning, and overturned the trunks with wind, so the forester packed her bag, and put on her warm, clean coat, and tucked her dagger into her belt, and went looking for another forest.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): For a place where everything made sense and the trees grew right, where she could tend a new grove in straight lines as it grew secure and upright and strong and beautiful and orderly.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Where she could tend a new growth.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In the morning, as she looked for the grove, she trusted it was just over the next hill.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And in the afternoon, she was sure it was around the next block of the city.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But as the day wore on, the place she looked for never appeared.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And then, under a twilight sky, she found a single sapling growing out of a crack in the rock, far from its home.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): How is she to help it?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Whose story is next?
Tim Sackton: I will sort of reluctantly step forward and kind of
Tim Sackton: Gnawed his head towards the automaton.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Charo, I will tell you a story about keeping everyone safe.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Once upon a time, there was a man who dearly wanted to keep his friends safe.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But whose neighbor on the hill kept a monster in her cellar, locked behind doors of stone and magic and iron.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The neighbor said that she was a doctor, and to learn how to heal a wound, she must first study how a wound is made. Over and over, she studied, and each time, when her experiments were done, she fed the remains of them to the monster in her cellar.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): At dinner, her guests made toasts to her. Your work is keeping us all safe. And they praised her with songs and stories of her deeds, but she swore them to secrecy, saying, The world will not understand what I do.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What I do, To keep them safe.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Your songs and stories must stay with me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She died very far from home, and if anyone ate her remains, I do not know that story.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In time, her friends forgot what was locked under the floor.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Her friends forgot the doors of stone and magic and iron.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Her friends forgot even where her house was, and then forgot that once they had been her friends, like the night, forgetting the day.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Until, once upon a time.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There was a man who dearly wanted to keep his friends safe under a twilight sky.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And what was he to do?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And Ari says, finally, Tarek, your story is the last, but we'll save it for next session.
David S. Kong: go through the door. We go through the door.
Tim Sackton: Let's go. Yeah. Now that we've made a decision, Charo's impatient. Let's get moving.
David S. Kong: Who normally goes first through things?
Mike: E-Trac, I'll go first.
David S. Kong: Nice. Who's carrying Arraya?
David S. Kong: Can we strap, like, a Ray on… actually, oh, Array doesn't have arms.
David S. Kong: Yeah, can we, like, strap a Ray? That's 45 pounds, right?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, you could rig,
David S. Kong: Yeah, we do that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): accepting that.
David S. Kong: Take a little backpack.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 5 minutes to do that?
Mike: Yeah.
David S. Kong: Great, perfect.
Mike: Why not?
David S. Kong: Yes! Guys, this is great, we have a fucking… we have an AI NPC with us now. This is… this is fucking epic.
Tim Sackton: You definitely are.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We're coming up at 10.30, and I have a… are we going to 10.30? 11.30? How late do you guys want to go?
Tim Sackton: Like, 11? Can we do…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, yeah.
Tim Sackton: I mean, you know the painting better than us.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think I have a good…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think I have a good place to stop here, because there's a…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): there's a choice, and I sort of feel it would be good to start with that, and stepping into the room, everyone together. Does that work?
David S. Kong: So you wanna stop here?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, I think, like, 10 more minutes.
Mike: Yeah?
David S. Kong: Great.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You cross through the library.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Pass the stacks and the shelves.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): you notice, in passing as you go, there's a whole shelf of books on cosmology by Ashara Ven.
David S. Kong: It's mandatory.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): coded and annotated and cross-referenced commentary of Upon the Fractured Earth.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's one shelf, which is just Journey of the Souls, a commentary in five volumes, immediately followed by Journey of the Souls, A Refugee
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): by volumes.
Tim Sackton: Sorry to be nipped, like, do you intend that there are books from…
Tim Sackton: recent? Like, from long after Drank War fell? Or no?
Tim Sackton: I don't know whether you're dropping…
Tim Sackton: I don't know whether you… okay, maybe… maybe Char doesn't know, so it doesn't matter anyway. Yeah, yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): it just as flavor. That's… that's more… more Easter eggs for the… for the real fans.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Tim, you need to add the dates of composition to your book entries in Telgarverse, is the real takeaway here.
Kate Sackton: They're not…
Tim Sackton: Wait… Oh, oh, this is all stuff, you probably were looking.
Mike: You don't have dates of compositions and things.
Mike: Like, I woke up this afternoon, okay, cool.
Tim Sackton: Oh, that one doesn't.
Tim Sackton: This one does. So, I haven't invented dates for everything yet.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh, you're right about Ashara, then… okay.
Mike: Oh, yeah, yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, I'll stand by Journey of the Souls, at least.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The Riven Veil! There's a whole shelf devoted to the works of Marciana Veridil.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Alright, moving on.
Tim Sackton: That's… that's good drancor context.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Thanks. The point being, you get across the room, passing these many little bits of flavor,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): To come to the door, As you get close to the door, There's an odd…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's an odd thing to it. When you get close.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You realize it's not one door exactly, but three different doors simultaneously, almost as if
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You could imagine it as 3 different doors.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): but all occupying the same space, as if it's, like, a superposition of several different things all at once. And each of them has a small window that you can look through, but
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What you see on the other side of that window is radically different from one to the next.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In the first, You see a child who's maybe… 9 or 10 years old.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sitting on sandy ground next to a well.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Playing with a stick.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Making shapes and drawing in the sand.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In the second door, You see, a young adult.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): fully grown… With their back to you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Dressed like a fae, but probably not a fae.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sitting at a drawing table, sketching.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And to their side, there's a wicker basket with something shiny in it that you can't make out.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And from time to time, this person will glance over, you see that from the back of their head, will glance over curiously, and you can see the curl of a smile coming up. The way,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know if you've ever had, like, a sleeping kitten next to you, and when you look at the thing, you can't help but just…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's joyful and delightful, and he'll reach in and touch this shining something, and then return to his work again.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The third door… is what looks like an ancient and decrepit old man, although the longer that you look.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): the more you realize this is actually a middle-aged person, this is probably someone in their late 30s or early 40s, who just looks incredibly old, like someone who's been living rough on the street for…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Years and years and years, in tattered clothes and pallid skin, unkempt, long hair missing in places, untrimmed, unwashed.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Wild-eyed, moving frantically, almost animal-like, twitchy, with a basket on his lap, with a lid over the top of it, open just a crack, and he'll open it and look in, and then slam it back shut and look all around himself again, as if fearful that someone's watching.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So, 3 doors.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The child, the young adult.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And the middle-aged.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Old man.
Mike: Now, these probably relate back to the different…
Mike: I have to, like, look at the notes.
Mike: All the different notes of the different…
Tim Sackton: there's not…
Mike: There's not a…
Tim Sackton: Old… well, I guess maybe the Thirst is the old man? Yeah.
Tim Sackton: Chara would lean towards the child.
Tim Sackton: Here's the notes.
Mike: and putting it in chat. I mean, I could just look at it and just…
David S. Kong: Yeah, the prisoner's probably the child, right?
Mike: Now, the child is probably the child.
David S. Kong: Oh.
Mike: I mean, it's all the prisoner, it's all the same person, it's different points of time, right?
Kate Sackton: They're superimposed, so we're just gonna put one key in one door and go through, like, we don't have to.
Mike: BS.
Kate Sackton: one personification.
Mike: You don't.
Kate Sackton: This is information, it's not decision, right?
Mike: I thought those 3 different…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Two different doors.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All of which occupy the same space, but are in fact 3 different doors.
Mike: Yeah, it feels to me like we're picking which one to go.
Tim Sackton: I think we should go through the child.
Mike: Yeah, sounds great.
Tim Sackton: I definitely don't want to go to the old man. The thirst is scary.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): who's gonna turn the key?
Tim Sackton: Me and Chara will, if no… I'm guessing Tarek probably would, but…
David S. Kong: Oh, that's a good point.
Tim Sackton: So Charles, happy to.
Mike: Future quail.
Kate Sackton: Any of us can.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What's your order?
David S. Kong: All Saint.
Tim Sackton: is usually…
Mike: I mean, E-Drick often goes to things first, but I don't know.
Tim Sackton: Dedrick at the front, Tara… Charo or Taric in the back, because they're decent perception.
Tim Sackton: The other one of those two second, and the two barbs in the safe spots in the middle.
Tim Sackton: I will say, for simplicity, Since Eric's not here, Char isn't back.
Tim Sackton: Keeping watch on what's behind us. Tarek is second.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): When you, when you head over, Charo, you realize
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): As you've been looking through the door and deciding on the possibility.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You realize all at once that Monistheus did not follow you.
David S. Kong: Where is that?
Tim Sackton: That's fine, I don't care.
Tim Sackton: Is he dead? He's probably dead.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And as the thought crosses your mind, and you turn back to the door, You're unexpectedly
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Reminded of his presence.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): As his arm, now impossibly long and stretched out, and articulated fingers wrap themselves around your body.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And he's completed.
Tim Sackton: Interesting.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): information.
Tim Sackton: I'm turning into a spider.
Tim Sackton: And I'm running to the door.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Awesome.
Tim Sackton: Go ahead and grab that, mushroom man.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A second hand, with, with fingers that are two feet long, whisks its way across the empty space where the first one was, trying to catch you,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm gonna roll a D20 just in case I get a natural 20, which I do not. Yeah, and completely, completely misses.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): through the door you go, and I think that's where.
Tim Sackton: Sorry, actually, it's not a spider, it's a tiny anole lizard.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Perfect.
Tim Sackton: One of those little micro-lizards.
Tim Sackton: So I… but I can climb on… I can climb on walls, too, so…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It still didn't hit, and he's far enough behind you that if you all want to hustle through the door and slam it behind you, you certainly can.
Mike: We didn't accept that.
Kate Sackton: Does that mean you dropped the… array?
David S. Kong: No, already strapped onto the… we jury-rigged a thing.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Raise the back.
Tim Sackton: Karen.
David S. Kong: It is a backpack.
Tim Sackton: Yeah.
Kate Sackton: Oh, I thought.
David S. Kong: Where is that?
Kate Sackton: I thought you were carrying a ray because you were the strong one.
Tim Sackton: No, I'm not strong. I'm just as weak. You're stronger than… any of us but EDREC.
Tim Sackton: Because you don't like taking eights, so you never have an 8 strength. The rest of us have 8 strength.
David S. Kong: Edric probably has array as a backpack.
Mike: No, Eatrick will carry it, right? It's fine.
Tim Sackton: Yeah.
David S. Kong: as a backpack.
Mike: Ajric has, like, a 17 string.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You swing the door shut behind you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): all five of you, plus RA, having made it successfully through
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With Monistheus now turned to a mushroom man on the far side.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And as the door swings shut behind you.
Kate Sackton: we…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You are left in complete…
Kate Sackton: E with it?
Kate Sackton: When we were using it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): the… doesn't work that way. To unlock the door, the key is engaged and can't be removed.
Kate Sackton: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That is, to open the door, the key has to remain in the lock engaged.
Kate Sackton: I tried.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And as the door swings shut behind you, you're plunged into a complete and utter darkness. Darker than black. Darker than anything you've ever experienced before.
Tim Sackton: But my lizard has 30 feet of darkvision, can I see through it?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think you need true sight to see through this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Or…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): there is nothing extant inside to be seen, although I guess you'd see the other party members. No, no, there's nothingness. It's entirely obscured.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And in that utter and complete darkness, I think is where I want to leave it and pick up with Eric next time.
Mike: Yeah?
Tim Sackton: Okay.
David S. Kong: Great.
Kate Sackton: Dude.
Mike: Sounds good.
David S. Kong: Guys, we went through a door.
Mike: We did, finally.
David S. Kong: You're…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In the 27th room!
Mike: We made it! We made it to the 27th room.
David S. Kong: Really?
David S. Kong: Nice. Awesome. But most importantly, we have an NPC now! We have an AI NPC!
Mike: Beautiful.
Tim Sackton: I think it's still gonna work without the sole power of the house. I think it's probably just an inert pile of gears now.
David S. Kong: We'll see, but then it's gonna be, Kato Min's, like, goal to reanimate it, and it's gonna be a whole adventure.
Mike: Yeah.
Mike: Sounds like…
Tim Sackton: And then, eventually, Seeker is gonna meet Kato Min, and then Vindra Sharna's gonna have a talking AI head.
David S. Kong: Yeah, all of these things are true, yes.
Mike: Yeah?
David S. Kong: Awesome.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Awesome.
Tim Sackton: Okay. Awesome.
Mike: Alright, I'm gonna go to bed, since we ended early, because I was tired, so… night ever.
Tim Sackton: Next week.
Tim Sackton: Kong and I are gonna figure some stuff out now, so we can have a very efficient Session Zero for Dragonettes.
Mike: Are we…
Mike: wait, super quickly, sorry, I know I just said I was gonna… is there, like, some idea? Are we, like, running with classes and stuff? Like, what should we be thinking about for a Dragonite character?
Tim Sackton: That's what I… that's what I'm gonna figure out… that's what Kong and I are gonna figure out right now, and we'll text people.
Mike: Text us, okay.
David S. Kong: Yeah, but worldbuilding…